Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Quartett for 4 Violins in G Minor, May 14, 1911; 1 score (24 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), violin 3 part (5 p.), and violin 4 part (7 p.) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in G Minor - Parts: Violin 1, May 14, 1911; 2.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in G Minor - Parts: Violin 2, May 14, 1911; 3.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in G Minor - Parts: Violin 3, May 14, 1911; 4.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in G Minor - Parts: Violin 4, May 14, 1911; 5.
- Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor, May 31, 1911; 1 score (20 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), violin 3 part (7 p.), and violin 4 part (7 p.) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Possibly first conceived as a string quartet (2 violins, viola, violoncello) as instrument names are given in score, then "Violin III" and "Violin IV" in black ink over pencil. Scores in pencil. Third movement score is in oblong format.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor - Score, May 31, 1911; 2.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor - Violin 1, May 31, 1911; 2.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor - Violin 2, May 31, 1911; 3.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor - Violin 3, May 31, 1911; 4.
  - Quartett for 4 Violins in D Minor - Violin 4, May 31, 1911; 5.
- Quartett: No. 1: in Ess Dur, June 6, 1870; violine 1 part (8 p.), violino secondo part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  The number "117" written in pencil on Violine I part. Location: New York. Faded.
  - Quartett: No. 1 - Parts: Violine 1, June 6, 1870; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 1 - Parts: Violino Secondo, June 6, 1870; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 1 - Parts: Viola, June 6, 1870; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 1 - Parts: Violoncello, June 6, 1870; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 2: in C Major, June 25, 1870; violin 1 part (11 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  The number "118" written in pencil on Violine I part. Location: New York.
  - Quartett: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 1, June 25, 1870; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 2, June 25, 1870; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 2 - Parts: Viola, June 25, 1870; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violoncello, June 25, 1870; 4.
- Quartett: No. 2: in C Dur, June 25, 1870; violine primo part, (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  The number "2" also written in red ink on caption of parts. Incomplete. Lacks Violin II part, and only has 2 pages of the violoncello part. At the 2nd page of the 4th movement, the Violin I part has some additional measures written in pencil. Location: New York.
  - Quartett: No. 2 - Parts: Violino Primo, June 25, 1870; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 2 - Parts: Viola, June 25, 1870; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 2 - Parts: Violoncello, June 25, 1870; 3.
- Quartett: No. 3: 2nd Serie: in F Dur, January 23, 1875; violine 1 part (10 p.), violino 2 part (10 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violincello part (8 p.) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  A working copy with measures crossed out in all parts. The number "193" written in pencil on wrapper. At head of title: Dedicated to my friend Frank Weyman.
  - Quartett: No. 3: 2nd serie - Parts: Violine 1, January 23, 1875; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 3: 2nd serie - Parts: Violino 2, January 23, 1875; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 3: 2nd serie - Parts: Viola, January 23, 1875; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 3: 2nd serie - Parts: Violoncello, January 23, 1875; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 3: in F Major, January 23, 1875; violin 1 part (11 p.), violin 2 part (11 p.), viola part (10 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  Final version of the work. The number "119" written in pencil on Violine I part. At head of title: To Mr. Frank B. Weyman.
  - Quartett: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 1, January 23, 1875; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 2, January 23, 1875; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 3 - Parts: Viola, January 23, 1875; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violoncello, January 23, 1875; 4.
- Quartett: No. 4: in F Dur: in Neuer Form: Manfred, December 29, 1885; violine 1 part (6 p.), violine 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violincello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  The number "120" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "4" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 4 - Parts: Violine 1, December 29, 1885; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 4 - Parts: Violine 2, December 29, 1885; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 4 - Parts: Viola, December 29, 1885; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 4 - Parts: Violoncello, December 29, 1885; 4.
- Quartett: No. 5: in F Moll: Undine, January 2, 1886; violine 1 part (6 p.), violine 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (4 p.) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  The number "121" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "5" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 5 - Parts: Violine 1, January 2, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 5 - Parts: Violine 2, January 2, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 5 - Parts: Viola, January 2, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 5 - Parts: Violoncello, January 2, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 6: [in Db Major]: Urganda the Fairy, June 16, 1886; violine 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  The number "122" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "6" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 6 - Parts: Violine 1, June 16, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 6 - Parts: Violine 2, June 16, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 6 - Parts: Viola, June 16, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 6 - Parts: Violoncello, June 16, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 7: in E Dur: Eine Sommernacht in Venedig, March 3, 1886; violine 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  The number "123" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "7" pasted in on parts. Contents: 1. Unter dem Volke Venedigs -- 2. Die Gondelfahrt bei Mondschein -- 3. Nächtlicher Empfang im Palais Royal.
  - Quartett: No. 7 - Parts: Violine Primo, March 3, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 7 - Parts: Violine 2, March 3, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 7 - Parts: Viola, March 3, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 7 - Parts: Violoncello, March 3, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No.8: [in D Major]: In der Heimath der Schweitz, March 20, 1886; violine 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  The number "124" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "8" pasted in on parts. Contents: 1. Der Morgen auf den Alpen -- 2. Das Hüten der Heerde -- 3. Volkesweisen.
  - Quartett: No.8 - Parts: Violine 1, March 20, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No.8 - Parts: Violine 2, March 20, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No.8 - Parts: Viola, March 20, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No.8 - Parts: Violoncello, March 20, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 9: [in C Minor]: Klosterleben, March 27, 1886; violine 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  The number "126" penciled in on Violine I part. The number "9" pasted in on parts. Contents: 1. Der Mönch -- 2. Die Nonne -- 3. Das Kloster.
  - Quartett: No. 9 - Parts: Violine 1, March 27, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 9 - Parts: Violine 2, March 27, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 9 - Parts: Viola, March 27, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 9 - Parts: Violoncello, March 27, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 10: [in E Moll]: Portia, April 12, 1886; violine 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  The number "126" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "10" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 10 - Parts: Violin 1, April 12, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 10 - Parts: Violin 2, April 12, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 10 - Parts: Viola, April 12, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 10 - Parts: Violoncello, April 12, 1886; 4.
- Presto: from D Minor Quartette (with ad lib Bass), 1 score (12 p.), violin 1 part (3 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.), and cello part (2 p.) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Score not in hand of composer. Score and parts are stamped "Max Shapiro." Parts are facsimiles.
  - Presto: from D Minor Quartette - Score, 1.
  - Presto: from D Minor Quartette - Parts: Violin 1, 2.
  - Presto: from D Minor Quartette - Parts: Violin 2, 3.
  - Presto: from D Minor Quartette - Parts: Viola, 4.
  - Presto: from D Minor Quartette - Parts: Violoncello, 5.
- Quartett: No. 11: [in A Minor]: Diana, October 27, 1886; violine 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  The number "127" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "11" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 11 - Parts: Violin 1, October 27, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 11 - Parts: Violin 2, October 27, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 11 - Parts: Viola, October 27, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 11 - Parts: Violoncello, October 27, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 12: [in F Major]: Medea, November 7, 1886; violine 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 10)
  The number "128" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "12" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 12 - Parts: Violine Primo, November 7, 1886; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 12 - Parts: Violine Secondo, November 7, 1886; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 12 - Viola, November 7, 1886; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 12 - Violoncello, November 7, 1886; 4.
- Quartett: No. 13: [in G Major], April 19, 1887; violine 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 11)
  The number "129" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "13" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 13 - Parts: Violine 1, April 19, 1887; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 13 - Parts: Violine 2, April 19, 1887; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 13 - Parts: Viola, April 19, 1887; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 13 - Parts: Violoncello, April 19, 1887; 4.
- Quartett: No. 14: [in E Minor]: Am Rhein, May 19, 1887; violine 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  The number "130" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "14" pasted in on parts.
  - Quartett: No. 14 - Parts: Violin 1, May 19, 1887; 1.
  - Quartett: No. 14 - Parts: Violin 2, May 19, 1887; 2.
  - Quartett: No. 14 - Parts: Viola, May 19, 1887; 3.
  - Quartett: No. 14 - Parts: Violoncello, May 19, 1887; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 15: in A Dur: Pastorale, October 10, 1875; violine 1 part (11 p.), violin 2 part (12 p.), viola part (11 p.), and violoncello part (10 p.) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  The number "131" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "15" pasted in on parts
  - Quartett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Violin 1, October 10, 1875; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Violin 2, October 10, 1875; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Viola, October 10, 1875; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 15 - Parts: Cello, October 10, 1875; 4.
- Quartetto: No. 16; [in E Major], March 23, 1866; violine 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 17, Folder 14)
  The number "132" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "16" pasted in on parts. Location: Augusta, GA (Norfolk, VA given at the end of each part).
  - Quartetto: No. 16 - Parts: Violino Primo, March 23, 1866; 1.
  - Quartetto: No. 16 - Parts: Violino Secondo, March 23, 1866; 2.
  - Quartetto: No. 16 - Parts: Viola, March 23, 1866; 3.
  - Quartetto: No. 16 - Parts: Violoncello, March 23, 1866; 4.
- Suter-Stroyd Quartett: [no.] 17: in E Minor, October 12, 1904; violine 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  The number "133" written in pencil on Violine I part. The number "17" pasted in on parts. Violin 1 part lacks variation 5 of Finale.
  - Suter-Stroyd Quartett - Parts: Violin 1, October 12, 1904; 1.
  - Suter-Stroyd Quartett - Parts: Violin 2, October 12, 1904; 2.
  - Suter-Stroyd Quartett - Parts: Viola, October 12, 1904; 3.
  - Suter-Stroyd Quartett - Parts: Violoncello, October 12, 1904; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 18 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello: in D Minor: Romeo and Juliet, October 18, 1904; violine 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 17, Folder 16)
  The number "134" written in pencil on cover. The number "18" pasted in on cover and parts. Illustration of Balcony scene from Romeo and Juliet pasted in on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 18 - Parts: Violin 1, October 18, 1904; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 18 - Parts: Violin 2, October 18, 1904; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 18 - Parts: Viola, October 18, 1904; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 18 - Parts: Violoncello, October 18, 1904; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 19: in Eb Major, October 21, 1903; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  The number "19" pasted in on parts. The number "88" penciled in on top-left corner of Violin I part.
  - Quartett: [no.] 19 - Parts: Violin 1, October 21, 1903; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 19 - Parts: Violin 2, October 21, 1903; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 19 - Parts: Viola, October 21, 1903; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 19 - Parts: Violoncello, October 21, 1903; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 20 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in Bb Major, May 10, 1904; violin 1 part (11 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  The number "372" in pencil on cover. The number "20" pasted in on cover and parts. At head of title: To Mothers Memory. Contents: 1. Allegro-con-moto et sentimentale-- 2. Adagio esspressione-- 3. Allegretto scherzando mystyrioso -- 4. Finale: Allegro spiritoso.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violin 1, May 10, 1904; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violin 2, May 10, 1904; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Viola, May 10, 1904; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violoncello, May 10, 1904; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 21: in A Minor: The Chums, November 8, 1904; violin 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  The number "21" pasted in on parts. The number "89" penciled in on top-left corner of Violin I part.
  - Quartett: [no.] 21 - Parts: Violin 1, November 8, 1904; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 21 - Parts: Violin 2, November 8, 1904; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 21 - Parts: Viola, November 8, 1904; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 21 - Parts: Violoncello, November 8, 1904; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 22: in A Minor: Italian, November 14, 1904; violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  The number "366" written in pencil on parts. Contents: 1. Allegro agitato -- 2. Introduction-recitation et adagio-cantabile -- 3. Allegretto barcarolle -- 4. Finale: Allegro-vivace quasi tarantella.
  - Quartett: [no.] 22 - Parts: Violin 1, November 14, 1904; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 22 - Parts: Violin 2, November 14, 1904; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 22 - Parts: Viola, November 14, 1904; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 22 - Parts: Violoncello, November 14, 1904; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 23 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello: in D Minor, Ruth, March 10, 1905; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  The number "23" pasted in on parts. The number "90" penciled in on top-left corner of Violin I part.
  - Quartett: [no.] 23 - Parts: Violin 1, March 10, 1905; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 23 - Parts: Violin 2, March 10, 1905; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 23 - Parts: Viola, March 10, 1905; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 23 - Parts: Violoncello, March 10, 1905; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 24 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in G Minor: The Watercarriers of Nazareth, March 16, 1905; violin 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  The number "24" pasted in on parts. The number "91" penciled in on cover. Illustration of pink rose pasted in on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 24 - Parts: Violin 1, March 16, 1905; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 24 - Parts: Violin 2, March 16, 1905; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 24 - Parts: Viola, March 16, 1905; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 24 - Parts: Violoncello, March 16, 1905; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 25 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in A Minor: La Majesté, March 23, 1905; violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  The number "25" pasted in on parts. The number "92" penciled in on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 25 - Parts: Violin 1, March 23, 1905; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 25 - Parts: Violin 2, March 23, 1905; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 25 - Parts: Viola, March 23, 1905; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 25 - Parts: Violoncello, March 23, 1905; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 26 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in A Minor The Desert, 1 score (26 p.), violine 1 part (6 p.), violine 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  Illustrated title page. Cover, score and parts stamped "Max Shapiro." 3rd movement titled "The recreation" at end of 2nd movement in the Violin I part. Contents: 1. The desert -- 2. The oasis -- 3. The Arab's prayer -- Finale.
  - Quartett: [no.] 26 - Score, 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 26 - Parts: Violin 1, 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 26 - Parts: Violin 2, 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 26 - Parts: Viola, 4.
  - Quartett: [no.] 26 - Parts: Violoncello, 5.
- Quartett: [no.] 28 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in D Minor, October 9, 1905; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  The number "28" pasted in on parts. The number "93" penciled in on cover. At head of title (in pencil): To. Mr. Harry Hetzel and William Spe[a]r."
  - Quartett: [no.] 28 - Parts: Violin 1, October 9, 1905; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 28 - Parts: Violin 2, October 9, 1905; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 28 - Parts: Viola, October 9, 1905; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 28 - Parts: Violoncello, October 9, 1905; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 29 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in A Minor, October 13, 1905; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  The number "373" written in pencil on cover. The number "29" pasted in on cover and parts. Small picture on cover. Contents: 1. Allegro vigoroso -- 2. Adagio pathetique -- 3. Scherzo presto -- 4. Finale: Maestoso et allegro-con-molto Appassianato.
  - Quartett: [no.] 29 - Parts: Violin 1, October 13, 1905; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 29 - Parts: Violin 2, October 13, 1905; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 29 - Parts: Viola, October 13, 1905; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 29 - Parts: Violoncello, October 13, 1905; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 31: in G Major, November 13, 1906; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 11)
  The number "31" pasted in on parts.The number "94" penciled in on top-left corner of Violin I part.
  - Quartett: [no.] 31 - Parts: Violin 1, November 13, 1906
  - Quartett: [no.] 31 - Parts: Violin 2, November 13, 1906; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 31 - Parts: Viola, November 13, 1906; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 31 - Parts: Violoncello, November 13, 1906; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 32: in A Minor, December 3, 1906; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Quartett: [no.] 32 - Parts: Violin 1, December 3, 1906
  - Quartett: [no.] 32 - Parts: Violin 2, December 3, 1906; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 32 - Parts: Viola, December 3, 1906
  - Quartett: [no.] 32 - Parts: Violoncello, December 3, 1906
- Quartett: [no.] 33 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in A Minor, February 23, 1907; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 18, Folder 13)
  The number "33" pasted in on parts.The number "96" penciled in on cover. At head of title: To Mr. William Spear. Silhouette of young man pasted on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 33 - Parts: Violin 1, February 23, 1907; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 33 - Parts: Violin 2, February 23, 1907; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 33 - Parts: Viola, February 23, 1907; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 33 - Parts: Violoncello, February 23, 1907; 4.
- Quartett: Op. 33 / Adolph M. Foerster, violin 1 part (11 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 18, Folder 14)
  In Foerster's hand? Parts are stamped: Max Shapiro.
  - Quartett: Op. 33 - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Quartett: Op. 33 - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Quartett: Op. 33 - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Quartett: Op. 33 - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 34 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in D Major, April 21, 1907; violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 18, Folder 15)
  The number "34" pasted in on parts. The number "97" penciled in on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 34 - Parts: Violin 1, April 21, 1907; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 34 - Parts: Violin 2, April 21, 1907; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 34 - Parts: Viola, April 21, 1907; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 34 - Parts: Violoncello, April 21, 1907; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 35 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in G Major, April 28, 1907; violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 18, Folder 16)
  The number "35" pasted in on parts. The number "98" penciled in on cover.
  - Quartett: [no.] 35 - Parts: Violin 1, April 28, 1907; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 35 - Parts: Violin 2, April 28, 1907; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 35 - Parts: Viola, April 28, 1907; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 35 - Parts: Violoncello, April 28, 1907; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 20 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in B-Flat Major, May 4, 1907; violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violin 1, May 4, 1907; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violin 2, May 4, 1907; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Viola, May 4, 1907; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 20 - Parts: Violoncello, May 4, 1907; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 37 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in C Major, Mährchen, May 25, 1907; violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part (10 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  The number "371" in pencil on cover. The number "37" pasted in on cover and parts. On caption of Violin I part: To Miss Autumn Heall. Contents: 1. Moderato con moto -- 2. Allegretto-fantastique -- 3. Scherzando allegro-giojoso-quasi-presto -- 4. Finale: Allegro-tempesto et allegro-pathetique.
  - Quartett: [no.] 37 - Parts: Violin 1, May 25, 1907; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 37 - Parts: Violin 2, May 25, 1907; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 37 - Parts: Viola, May 25, 1907; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 37 - Parts: Violoncello, May 25, 1907; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 38 for 2 Quartett: [no.] 38: in D Major: for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in D Major, April 11, 1908; violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  The number "38" pasted in on parts. The number "9" penciled in on t.p. and parts.
  - Quartett: [no.] 38 - Parts: Violin 1, April 11, 1908; 1.
  - Quartett: [no.] 38 - Parts: Violin 2, April 11, 1908; 2.
  - Quartett: [no.] 38 - Parts: Viola, April 11, 1908; 3.
  - Quartett: [no.] 38 - Parts: Violoncello, April 11, 1908; 4.
- Quartett: [no.] 39 for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello in D Minor, 1 score (27 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 19, Folder 3)